

"Success is the sum of small efforts repeated day in and day out."
- Robert Collier

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

My passion began many years ago with web design and evolved into a curiosity for how to "build stuff". I love being immersed in the programming world and am seeking a Junior Developer or internship opportunity. I am dedicated to learning my craft and would love to contribute to a team while building upon my current skill set.

Skills include:

Full-Stack Web Development, Object-Oriented Programming / Test Driven Development / Digital Project Management / Online Marketing Collateral / Graphic Design

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks & Tools: Ruby on Rails, jQuery, PostgresSQL, Heroku, AWS, Twitter Bootstrap, Git / Github Middleman, WordPress, Photoshop

EDUCATION

Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY, 2003-2007 Martin J. Whitman School of Management Bachelor of Science; Entrepreneurship & Emerging Enterprises Dean's List

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Web Development, Algorithm, and Data Structures Foundations - Firehose Project, June - Oct 2015

An intensive 15-week program in which I am studying to become a programmer. I have learned how to develop web applications, break down complex problems into more manageable pieces and many tools of the trade.

- Learned how to build-out CRUD Rails apps following standard Rails conventions (without scaffolding), involving mailers, validations, image uploading on AWS S3 and nested RESTful routes.
- Implemented tests using MiniTest's Test::Unit Syntax for both unit and functional tests.
- Learned front-end development fundamentals and implemented responsive design in web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Biz Dev Now, Remote, March 2014 - Present

Digital Project Manager

Manage web development, graphic design and digital marketing projects from set-up to delivery for Biz Dev Now and it's clients; Source and hire freelancers. Expert WordPress set-up and maintenance. Graphic asset creation skills.

SmartsiteMovement, Aug 2012 - Sep 2014

Founder

Created standalone mobile websites for small businesses.

Progressive Business Publications, Malvern, PA, Feb 2011 - Sep 2012

Market Analyst

Managed email marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 to mid-sized companies. Revised marketing copy for struggling email marketing campaigns to improve lead generation results. Designed landing pages and conducted newsletter updates on WordPress site.

FedSources, Washington, DC Metro, 2010 - 2011

Market Intelligence Analyst

Analyzed and tracked federal government opportunities released by U.S. Navy agencies. Conducted in-depth internet and primary research for clients. Built professional relationships with Navy Contracting Officers. Attended industry conferences and publish reports for company website.

Help Unlimited Temps & Office Team, Washington, DC Metro, 2008 - 2009

Administrative Assistant

Temp Assignments:

DC Housing Finance Agency

Provided assistance to public regarding real estate buyer program and admin support to agency.

Giuliani Associates Architects Inc.

Data entry, AP/AR, payroll assistance, project folder maintenance

ComputerTraining.com, Newark, DE, 2007 - 2008

Assistant Director of Admissions

Conducted education sales for Microsoft Certification Program. Managed large database of potential students leads and schedule campus visits for Director of Admissions. Provided solid follow-up with potential students. Met and exceeded student enrollment goals.